Okay. Hi, everyone.
好的。嗨，大家好。
Let's get started again.
让我们重新开始吧。
Okay, so first of all let me just say a bit about Assignment 5.
好的，首先让我先谈谈作业5。
So Assignment 5 is coming out today.
所以作业5今天即将发布。
Um, it's a brand new assignment,
嗯，这是一个全新的任务，
so you guys are the guinea pigs for that.
所以你们这些是豚鼠。
Um, and so what it's going to be, it essentially builds on Assignment 4.
嗯，所以它将会是什么，它基本上建立在作业4上。
Um, so it's okay if you didn't do perfectly on Assignment 4,
嗯，如果你没有在作业4上做得很好，那也没关系，
but I think actually most people did.
但我认为大多数人都这样做了。
Um, and what we're gonna be doing is adding, um,
嗯，我们要做的就是补充一下，嗯，
convolutional neural networks and subword
卷积神经网络和子词
modeling to the neural machine translation system,
建模到神经机器翻译系统，
seeking it to make it better.
寻求它使它变得更好。
Um, so this assignment is coding heavy, written questions light.
嗯，所以这个任务编写繁重的书面问题。
Um, so I mean the coding that you have
嗯，所以我的意思是你所拥有的编码
to do sort of isn't actually really more difficult than Assignment 4,
做什么实际上并不比分配4更难，
it's kind of like Assignment 4.
这有点像作业4。
But what we're hoping is that this time you will be able to do it on your own.
但我们希望这次你能够自己做到这一点。
Now what I mean by that,
我的意思是，
um, is for Assignment 4.
嗯，是作业4。
Well, there was tons of scaffolding telling you what everything should be,
好吧，有大量的脚手架告诉你应该是什么，
and there were all of these auto-grader checks and you could keep on working on
并且有所有这些自动分级员检查，你可以继续工作
your code until they passed all the autograder checks, and everybody did.
你的代码，直到他们通过所有的自动编程检查，每个人都做了。
Um, and so it was very kind of coddled, shall we say.
嗯，所以它非常娇宠，我们可以说。
Um, but I mean,
嗯，但我的意思是，
I guess what we're really wanting to achieve is to have a more- sorry, question.
我想我们真正希望实现的目标是提出一个更令人遗憾的问题。
[inaudible]?
[听不清]？
Yes. So what we're hoping is that this can be, uh, useful.
是。所以我们希望这可以，呃，有用。
Um, it'll be short-term pain but useful as being
嗯，这将是短暂的痛苦但是有用
a more effective ramp to doing
做得更有效
the final project and indeed for the rest of your life, right.
最后的项目，确实是你的余生，对吧。
And the- the reality is that in the rest of your life,
而现实是，在你的余生中，
you sort of if you're going to be doing things with deep learning,
如果你要用深度学习做事，你会有点兴奋，
you kind of have to work out what kind of
你有点想弄出什么样的
model to build and which pieces to stitch together,
建造模型和拼接的部分，
and how to write some tests to see if it's doing something sensible.
以及如何编写一些测试来看看它是否做了明智的事情。
And if it's not doing something sensible, um,
如果它没有做一些明智的事，嗯，
to figure out how you could change things and try different things,
弄清楚如何改变事物并尝试不同的事物，
and get it to work sensibly.
让它明智地工作。
And so that's what we're hoping,
这就是我们所希望的，
um, that people, um,
嗯，那个人，嗯，
can do in Assignment 5,
可以在作业5中做，
so you've got to,
所以你必须这样做，
um, figure things out.
嗯，搞清楚。
Um, should write your own testing code.
嗯，应该编写自己的测试代码。
Um, we don't have a public autograder,
嗯，我们没有公共自动贩卖机，
so you should- that's part of working out your own sanity checks,
所以你应该 - 这是你自己的理智检查的一部分，
trying to do things like what I talked about last week of sort of getting
试着去做我上周谈到的那种事情
simple bits working, confirming that they work on
简单的工作，确认他们的工作
minute amounts of test data and so on, and doing things more sensibly.
微量的测试数据等，并做得更明智。
I mean in particular,
我的意思是，
um, the one particular part of that,
嗯，其中一个特别的部分，
that we were planning to do, um, for,
我们打算做的，嗯，因为，
um, this assignment, I was looking for it,
嗯，这个任务，我一直在找，
um, but it's on the next slide.
嗯，但它是在下一张幻灯片上。
Um, so, um, for this assignment and beyond, um,
嗯，所以，嗯，对于这项任务以及更远，嗯，
we're going to enforce rules like more like they are in CS107,
我们将执行更像CS107中的规则，
for those of you who are undergrads,
对于那些本科生来说，
meaning that the TAs don't look at and debug your code for you.
这意味着TA不会为您查看和调试代码。
Um, and so, you know,
嗯，你知道，
of course we still want TAs to be helpful, come to them with your problems, um,
当然，我们仍然希望助教有帮助，带着你的问题来找他们，嗯，
talk about how you're meant to use different things,
谈谈你如何使用不同的东西，
um, in the PyTorch library,
嗯，在PyTorch图书馆，
um, but you shouldn't be regarding it as the TA's job of, here's a big Python file.
嗯，但你不应该把它视为TA的工作，这是一个很大的Python文件。
Um, can you tell me what's wrong with it,
嗯，你能告诉我它有什么问题吗？
and fix it up for you.
并为你解决。
Okay. Um, the precise policy for that's,
好的。嗯，这个的确切政策，
um, written up on Piazza.
嗯，写在广场上。
Okay. So after- any questions about that or do I go straight on in?
好的。那么之后 - 有关于此的任何问题或我是否会直接进入？
Okay. Um, yes so today's lecture,
好的。嗯，是的，今天的讲座，
um, in some sense today's lecture is an easy lecture.
嗯，在某种意义上，今天的讲座是一个简单的讲座。
Um, so last time's lecture,
嗯，所以上次讲座，
there was really sort of a ton of new stuff
真的有很多新东西
of other stuff on neural networks that you haven't seen before,
你以前没见过的神经网络上的其他东西，
and we did Convnets and we did pooling layers,
我们做了Convnets，我们做了汇集层，
and we did highway and residual connections,
我们做了高速公路和剩余连接，
and batch norms, and I don't know, whatever else we did.
和批量规范，我不知道，我们做了什么。
Um, size one convolutions I guess.
嗯，我想是一个大小的卷积。
So there are tons of new stuff really
所以真的有很多新东西
in this lecture in terms of sort of neural network machinery,
在这个讲座中，神经网络机器的种类，
there isn't any new stuff at all.
没有任何新东西。
So this is really easy.
所以这很容易。
Um, and this is also really a new lecture but it was sort of put in for a reason.
嗯，这也是一个新的讲座，但它有点理由。
And the reason for this relates to a kinda remark I made
其原因与我所作的一种评论有关
last time about how lots of stuff keeps changing in neural network land.
上一次关于神经网络领域中有多少东西不断变化的问题。
So at the time we first designed this class and
所以当时我们第一次设计这个课程和
the way as- that a lot of the structure of it still is.
因为它的很多结构仍然存在。
Um, that sort of around 2014-2015 when we designed this class,
嗯，就在2014  -  2015年我们设计这个课程时，
it was basically axiomatic that
这基本上是公理化的
all deep learning models for natural language processing worked off words.
所有用于自然语言处理的深度学习模型都能解决问题。
And therefore it completely made sense that we start with word vectors,
因此，我们从单词向量开始是完全有意义的，
and then we start looking at things like recurrent models over words.
然后我们开始研究复发模型等词语。
Whereas the fact of the matter is in the last approximately three years,
事情的事实是在过去大约三年，
there's been a ton of new work including some of the most influential new work.
有大量的新作品，包括一些最有影响力的新作品。
There's building language models that aren't- isn't -isn't aren't, um,
那些不是的建筑语言模型 - 不是 - 不是，嗯，
being built over words that they're building, built over pieces of words or characters.
建立在他们正在建造的文字上，建立在文字或字符之上。
And so this lecture is sort of meant to give you
所以这个讲座有点意味着给你
some sense of these other ways of doing things and,
对这些其他做事方式的一些感觉，
um, some orientation to some of the things that's going on.
嗯，对一些正在发生的事情有所了解。
But the actual kind of models that we're looking at, uh,
但是我们正在看的实际模型，呃，
sort of using all of the building blocks that we've already looked at, things like,
使用我们已经看过的所有构建块，比如，
um, RNNs and ConvNets and things like that.
嗯，RNN和ConvNets等等。
So let's get into this.
所以让我们进入这个。
Um, so I'm going to start off with a teeny bit
嗯，所以我要开始一点点
of linguistics of learning about the structure of language, um,
学习语言结构的语言学，嗯，
at first sort of lower level units of language and then we'll see how that pans out,
在第一种较低级别的语言单元，然后我们将看到如何平移，
um, for things like character level models.
对于角色等级模型这样的东西。
So in linguistics, um,
那么在语言学方面，嗯，
if you start at the bottom of the totem pole,
如果你从图腾柱的底部开始，
the first-level of linguistics is phonetics,
第一级语言学是语音学，
which is sort of understanding the sounds and the physiology of human speech.
这有点理解人类语音的声音和生理学。
So that's sort of like physics, or physiology,
所以这有点像物理学或生理学，
or something, right, there are mouth parts that move,
或某事，对，有嘴部分移动，
there are ear parts that act as filters,
有耳部作为过滤器，
and there's, um, audio waves in between the two of them.
嗯，这两者之间有音频波。
So that's kind of uncontroversial in some sense.
从某种意义上讲，这是毫无争议的。
Um, but above that level,
嗯，但高于那个水平，
the standard thing that people do for the analysis of human languages is to say,
人们为分析人类语言所做的标准事情就是说，
well human languages may seem to make use of a relatively small set of
好的人类语言似乎可以利用相对较小的一组
distinctive units which are then commonly called phonemes which are actually categorical.
然后通常称为音素的独特单元实际上是分类的。
And the idea here is that well,
这里的想法很好，
uh, our mouths are continuous spaces, right.
呃，我们的嘴是连续的空间，对。
That they've got these various bits of their mouths like, you know,
你知道，他们有各种各样的嘴巴
tongues and pharynges and so on,
舌头和咽喉等等，
but it's a continuous space.
但这是一个连续的空间。
So actually, um, we can make an infinite variety of sounds, right.
所以实际上，嗯，我们可以发出无数种声音，对吧。
So if I open my mouth and apply voicing and just wiggle my tongue around, I can go [NOISE].
因此，如果我张开嘴并施加嗓音，只是扭动我的舌头，我就可以[NOISE]。
And I can make an infinite variety of different sounds.
我可以制作各种不同的声音。
But the reality is that human languages aren't like that,
但现实是人类语言不是那样的，
that out of that infinite variety of sounds,
那种无穷无尽的声音，
we distinguish a small space of sounds.
我们区分了一小段声音。
Um, and something that happens when languages change is, um,
嗯，当语言改变时发生的事情是，嗯，
that the space of sounds that are seen as
被视为的声音空间
important and distinguished in a language change.
语言变化中的重要和杰出。
And that happens even with inside one language as- as English.
即使用一种语言 - 就像英语一样，这种情况也会发生。
And I'm about to give an example of that.
我即将举一个例子。
Um, so people in cog psych talk about the phenomenon of categorical perception.
嗯，因此cog psych的人们谈论分类感知的现象。
And what that means is that really there's something continuous,
这意味着什么是真的有连续的东西，
but that humans perceive it as belonging to fairly sharp categories.
但人类认为它属于相当尖锐的类别。
Um, and, you know,
嗯，你知道，
you can use that for sort of, you know,
你知道，你可以使用它
styles of clothing or whether someone counts as fat or not.
服装的风格或者是否有人认为是否有脂肪。
Um, but the most famous examples of categorical perception are in language,
嗯，但最着名的分类感知的例子是语言，
where we can make an infinite variety of sounds but
在哪里我们可以发出无数种声音但是
people per- perceive them as categories.
人们将他们视为类别。
And so effectively what that means is when you have categorical perception,
当你有分类感知时，这意味着什么呢？
the differences within a category are sort of perceived to have shrunk.
一个类别中的差异有点被认为已经缩小。
You barely notice them at all where differences
你几乎没有注意到它们的差异
across categories are expanded and very clear.
跨类别的扩展和非常明确。
And so one of the cases that sort of studied
所以研究的案例之一
a lot is what's called- referred to as sort of,
所谓的很多 - 被称为，
um, voice onset time.
嗯，发声时间。
So lots of languages including English have pairs of sounds like p and b, uh,
所以包括英语在内的很多语言都有成对的声音，比如p和b，呃，
pah and bah, and they differ based on when voicing starts.
pah和bah，他们根据发声开始时的不同而不同。
So buh, it has a voice sound like a vowel with an r in it.
所以，它有一个声音，就像一个带有r的元音。
And well that's a continuous parameter,
这是一个连续的参数，
you can sort of make any point along a spectrum between a p and a b but, um,
你可以在ap和ab之间的频谱上做任何一点，但是，嗯，
human beings, um, who speak English,
人类，嗯，会说英语，
um, perceive just two points on that spectrum.
嗯，在这个频谱上只感知两点。
And you don't sort of really notice the fine differences between them.
你并没有真正注意到它们之间的细微差别。
Um, some languages distinguish more points on the spectrum.
嗯，一些语言区分了频谱上的更多点。
So Thai distinguishes three different consonant sounds,
所以泰语区分了三种不同的辅音，
um, in depending on the voice onset time.
嗯，取决于发声时间。
Um, something that might be, um,
嗯，可能是，嗯，
more accessible to you is,
你更容易接近，
um, this is an example of language change.
嗯，这是语言变化的一个例子。
So for a speaker like me, um,
对于像我这样的演讲者，嗯，
there was caught and cot and those are different vowels,
有被抓住和婴儿床，这些是不同的元音，
and I hear them as different vowels.
我听到他们是不同的元音。
But if you are someone who grew up in the southwest of the United States,
但如果你是在美国西南部长大的人，
um, then these are exactly the same vowel and you don't distinguish them.
嗯，那么这些是完全相同的元音，你不区分它们。
Then- you thought I said the same thing twice even though I'm saying two different vowels.
然后 - 你以为我说过两次同样的事情，尽管我说的是两个不同的元音。
And so that's where in even at a dialectal issue- level that people develop
因此，即使是在人们发展的方言问题上也是如此
categorical perception as to
分类感知
which- which distinctions and sounds they're sensitive to or not sensitive to.
哪些区别和声音对他们敏感或不敏感。
Okay. And summing- and,
好的。总结 - 和，
I mean why I'm mentioning this is in some senses these sound distinctions of
我的意思是为什么我提到这是在某些意义上这些声音的区别
categorical sound distinctions that are what a lot of
分类的声音区别是很多
our language writing systems that we'll come to in a minute record.
我们的语言编写系统，我们将在一分钟内记录。
Okay. Um, so in traditional linguistics, um,
好的。嗯，所以在传统语言学中，嗯，
you have sounds, but sounds don't have any meanings in language.
你有声音，但声音在语言中没有任何意义。
So pah and bah don't have meanings,
所以pah和bah没有意义，
and a and e don't have meanings.
和a和e没有意义。
And so people then normally distinguish as
因此人们通常会将其区分为
the next level up morphology is parts of words.
下一级的形态学是单词的一部分。
And this is seen as the minimal level that has meaning.
这被视为具有意义的最低级别。
And so the idea is lots of words are complex and can be made
因此，这个想法很多词很复杂，可以制作
u- made up of pieces but these pieces do have meanings.
u-由碎片组成，但这些碎片确实有意义。
So fortune has a meaning, um, fortunate,
财富有意义，嗯，幸运，
you end in this ate ending,
你结束了这个结局，
um, which sort of gives the- gives fortune to somebody.
嗯，哪种给予了 - 给某人带来了财富。
So that means you know, having fortune, um,
这意味着你知道，有财富，嗯，
that has a meaning,
那有意义，
un has a meaning which means to reverse that.
un具有意义，意味着扭转这一点。
So unfortunate means that you don't have fortune, and ly, um,
所以不幸意味着你没有财富，嗯，嗯，
then has a meaning of turning this all into an adverb,
然后有把这一切变成副词的意思，
and you can say unfortunately not having,
并且你可以说不幸没有，
um, gotten fortune, something happened.
嗯，得到了财富，发生了什么事。
And so these sort of pieces of, um,
所以这些，嗯，
words are then the minimal things that have meaning.
那些词就是有意义的最小的东西。
Um, almost no work in deep learning has tried to
嗯，几乎没有深度学习的工作试过
make use of this sort of morpheme level of structure.
利用这种语素层次的结构。
Actually me and a couple of students six years ago did actually
实际上，六年前我和几个学生确实做过
try and build a system where it built these tree structured neural networks,
尝试构建一个构建这些树形结构神经网络的系统，
that put together meanings of words out of their pieces.
把文字的意义放在一起。
Um, but that really isn't an idea that's taken on widely.
嗯，但这真的不是一个广泛采用的想法。
There's sort of a reason why it hasn't taken on widely,
有一个原因，它没有广泛，
which is doing this and working out the semantically meaningful pieces of words,
这样做并制定出语义上有意义的单词，
is kind of hard and a lot of the time in NLP what people have found
在NLP中，人们发现了很多困难和很多时间
is you can just about get the same kind of
是你可以得到同样的
results if you just work with character n-grams.
结果如果你只是使用字符n-gram。
The kind of units that you put into the convolutional neural net.
你放入卷积神经网络的那种单位。
Because if you just have a model that uses, um,
因为如果你只有一个使用的模型，嗯，
character trigrams and you have sort of start of word, un, and nfo, and so on.
字符三元组，你有一些单词，un和nfo的开头，等等。
For going through the ly end of word,
为了通过单词的结尾，
that those different units.
那些不同的单位。
There's different character trigrams,
有不同的人物三卦，
in a distributed way will pick up
以分布式的方式将提升
all the important meaning components of the word pretty well,
这个词的所有重要意义成分相当不错，
and that that's just good enough.
那就够了。
And that's actually a very classic idea that's sort of been revived.
而这实际上是一种非常经典的想法，有点复活了。
Um, so back in the second coming of
嗯，所以回到第二次来了
neural networks in the mid-80s into the early 90s, um,
神经网络在80年代中期到90年代初期，嗯，
there was qu- um,
有人，
there was quite a bit of sort of controversial work on
有很多有争议的工作
the structure of language and in particular Dave Rumelhart and Jay McClelland.
语言的结构，尤其是Dave Rumelhart和Jay McClelland。
So Jay McClelland's still in the psych department here,
所以Jay McClelland还在这里的心理科，
if you want to look him up in your spare time.
如果你想在业余时间看他。
Um, they proposed a model of how to model generating past tense forms in English.
嗯，他们提出了一个如何用英语建立过去时形式的模型。
So this was sort of a cog-psych experiment of can we build
所以这是我们可以建立的一种齿轮心理实验
a system that can learn past tenses of English verbs?
一个可以学习英语动词过去时态的系统？
And the difficult part there is some, many verbs are regular,
而困难的部分有一些，很多动词是常规的，
you add the kinda -ed ending,
你添加有点结尾，
but some words are irregular and you had to sort of learn about the irregular patterning.
但有些词是不规则的，你必须要了解不规则的图案。
Um, but the way they did that.
嗯，但他们这样做的方式。
I mean partly because this was sort of early days with respect to, um, sequence models,
我的意思是部分因为这是关于序列模型的早期日子，
is that they used a representation where they represented
是他们使用了他们所代表的代表
words precisely with these sort of character trigrams.
准确地说这些字符三元组。
And that was the representation of words that they used and fed forward in their model.
这就是他们在模型中使用并向前推进的单词的表示。
And that, um, idea was met with a lot of controversy by
那个，嗯，这个想法遭到了很多争议
linguists, philosophers, and other people with their ideas of
语言学家，哲学家和其他有他们想法的人
language and so there was a lot of debate in those days about that.
语言，所以那时候有很多争论。
But from a- as a purely engineering solution that
但是从a-作为纯粹的工程解决方案
sort of proved to be a pretty good way to do things.
事实证明这是一种非常好的做事方式。
And so this decade there's been other work which includes the model, um,
所以这十年还有其他工作包括模型，嗯，
developed at Microsoft of a sort of a deep, um,
微软开发的一种深度，嗯，
semantics model where what they're using as these kind of
语义模型，他们正在使用这些类型的东西
character n-grams to put meaning over words.
字符n-gram将意义置于文字之上。
Okay so, um, so now we might be interested in building models that aren't over words.
好的，嗯，现在我们可能有兴趣建立不超过单词的模型。
So we're going to have a word written as characters
所以我们要写一个字作为字符
and we're going to do something with it such as build character n-grams.
我们将用它来做一些事情，例如构建字符n-gram。
And so something that is just useful, um,
所以有用的东西，嗯，
to know is there's actually
要知道实际上是这样的
a fair amount of variation between languages when you do this.
执行此操作时，语言之间存在相当大的差异。
So it's not all the same stuff, right?
所以这不是一回事，对吧？
So the first problem is, um,
所以第一个问题是，嗯，
there are some languages that don't put spaces between words.
有些语言不会在单词之间放置空格。
The most famous example is Chinese.
最着名的例子是中国人。
Um, but an interesting fact for those people of European ancestry, um,
嗯，但对于那些欧洲血统的人来说这是个有趣的事实，嗯，
is that you know if- for- when the ancient Greeks wrote ancient Greek,
你知道，如果古希腊人写古希腊语，
um, they didn't put spaces between words either.
嗯，他们也没有在单词之间放置空格。
It was actually a later invention of
它实际上是后来的发明
medieval scholars who are recopying their manuscripts,
中世纪学者正在重新复制他们的手稿，
who they decided [NOISE] maybe that'll be easier to read if we
他们决定[噪音]他们可能会更容易阅读，如果我们
put spaces in and then they started doing it.
把空间放进去，然后他们就开始做了。
Um, [NOISE] most languages these days do put spaces in between words but even,
嗯，[NOISE]这些天大多数语言确实在单词之间放置了空格，但即便如此，
then there's sort of a lot of fine cases.
然后有很多很好的案例。
So in particular, a lot of languages have some sort of little bits
所以特别是，很多语言都有一些小问题
of stuff which might be pronouns, or prepositions,
可能是代词或介词的东西，
or various kind of joining words like and, and so,
或者各种各样的加入词，等等，
and which sometimes they write together and sometimes separately.
有时他们一起写，有时一起写。
So in French, um,
所以用法语，嗯，
you get these kind of prepositional, I'm sorry,
你得到这种介词，对不起，
pronominal, um, markers for you, I, you, have brought.
代词，嗯，标记为你，我，你，带来了。
Um, and you know, these kind of little words and
嗯，你知道，这些小词和
pronunciation just sort of run together as je vous ai,
发音只是像je vous ai一样运行，
and arguably it's almost one word,
可以说这几乎是一个字，
but it's written as separate words.
但它是作为单独的单词写的。
Um, where there are other languages which sort of stick things together,
嗯，还有其他语言可以把东西粘在一起，
where arguably they're separate words.
可以说他们是单独的词。
So in Arabic, you get pronominal clitics and some of these sort of joining words like so,
所以在阿拉伯语中，你会得到代词的clitics ，以及其中一些像这样的加入词，
and and, and they are sort of written together as one word,
而且，它们就像一个字一样写在一起，
where arguably that they should really be four words.
可以说他们应该真的是四个字。
Another famous case of that is with compound nouns.
另一个着名的案例是复合名词。
Um, so in English,
嗯，所以用英文，
we write compound nouns with spaces between them,
我们写复合名词，它们之间有空格，
so you can see each noun.
所以你可以看到每个名词。
Um, even though in many respects compound nouns
嗯，即使在许多方面复合名词
something like whiteboard behaves like it's one word, or high-school.
像白板这样的东西就像是单词或高中。
Um, whereas other languages,
嗯，而其他语言，
German is the most famous case,
德语是最着名的案例，
but also other Germanic languages,
还有其他日耳曼语言，
just write them all as one word and you get very long words like that.
把它们全部写成一个单词就可以得到很长的单词。
So we can get different words if we just use spaces and don't do much else. Um, good.
因此，如果我们只使用空格而不做其他事情，我们可以得到不同的词。嗯，好的。
Okay. Yes. So for dealing with words,
好的。是。所以对于处理单词，
there are these practical problems.
有这些实际问题。
Um, and we sort of already started to
嗯，我们已经开始了
touch on them that if you're trying to build word-based models,
触摸它们，如果你正在尝试构建基于单词的模型，
there's this huge space of words,
这是一个巨大的文字空间，
and well, strictly there's an infinite space of words
而且，严格来说，这是一个无限的单词空间
because once you allow in things like numbers,
因为一旦你允许像数字这样的东西，
let alone FedEx routing numbers, or, um,
更不用说联邦快递的路由号码，或者，嗯，
or if you allow just morphology,
或者如果你只允许形态学，
when you can make those ones like unfortunately.
什么时候你可以做那些不幸的。
Yeah, sort of, you can just expand the space of words,
是的，有点，你可以扩大单词的空间，
so you get this large open vocabulary.
所以你得到这个庞大的开放词汇。
Um, English, you know, a bit problematic.
嗯，英语，你知道，有点问题。
It gets way more problematic than a lot of other languages.
它比许多其他语言更容易出问题。
So here's a lovely Czech word, um,
所以这是一个可爱的捷克语，嗯，
to the worst farmable one, um,
到最糟糕的一个，嗯，
where you can make sort of much more complex words in lots of other languages.
在那里你可以用许多其他语言制作更复杂的单词。
Um, many Native American languages,
嗯，很多美洲土着语言，
other European languages like Finnish have these sort of very complex words,
像芬兰语这样的其他欧洲语言有这些非常复杂的单词，
Turkish has very complex words.
土耳其语有很复杂的词。
Um, so that's bad news.
嗯，这是个坏消息。
Um, there are other more reasons we'd like to be able to
嗯，还有其他更多我们想要的理由
look at words below the word level,
看看单词级别下面的单词，
to know things about them.
了解他们的事情。
So when you're translating,
所以当你翻译时，
there's a wide space of things,
这里有很多东西，
especially names, where translation is essentially transliteration,
特别是名字，其中翻译基本上是音译，
that you're going to rewrite the sound of somebody's name as just roughly, you know,
你要重写一个人名字的声音，你知道，
perhaps not perfectly correctly but roughly correctly
也许不是完全正确但大致正确
according to the sound systems of the different language.
根据不同语言的音响系统。
And well, if we want to do that,
好吧，如果我们想这样做，
we essentially want to work- operate at the letter level,
我们基本上想要在字母层面上工作，
not the word level.
不是单词级别。
But another huge modern reason why we'd like to start modeling below the word level is,
但是，我们想要在单词级别下开始建模的另一个巨大的现代原因是，
we live in this age of social media and if you're in the social media land,
我们生活在这个社交媒体时代，如果你在社交媒体领域，
there's a lot of stuff that's written not
有很多东西都写不了
using the canonical words that you find in the dictionary,
使用你在字典中找到的规范词，
and somehow we'd wanna start,
不知何故，我们想要开始，
um, to model that.
嗯，模仿那个。
So in some sense this is the, um,
所以在某种意义上说，这是，嗯，
easy case.
容易的情况。
Um, good vibes.
嗯，好振动。
Um, but nevertheless this is spelled with one,
嗯，但是这拼写了一个，
two, three, four, five, six,
二，三，四，五，六，
seven O's, and one, two,
七个O，一个，两个，
three, four, five, oh and also seven S's, they match.
三，四，五，哦，还有七个S，它们匹配。
I don't know if that's deliberate or not [LAUGHTER]. Um, okay.
我不知道这是否是故意的[笑声]。嗯，好的。
So this sty le of writing is very common, um, and well,
所以这种写作风格很常见，嗯，好吧，
you know, we kind of sunk if we're
你知道，如果我们这样的话，我们就会沉没
treating things at the word level and we're trying to model this right.
在单词级别处理事物，我们正在尝试对此进行建模。
That's clearly not what human beings are doing, we're sort of looking at
这显然不是人类正在做的事情，我们有点看
the characters and recognizing what goes on.
人物并认识到发生了什么。
Um, in some sense that's kind of the easy case that you could imagine preprocessing out.
嗯，从某种意义上说，这是一种你可以想象预处理的简单案例。
Um, there's a lot of harder stuff that then turns up.
嗯，有很多更难的东西然后出现。
Um, I guess there's sort of the abbreviation speak, like I don't care.
嗯，我猜有些缩写说话，就像我不在乎。
Um, but then you sort of get a lot of creative spellings, um,
嗯，但是你得到了很多创造性的拼写，嗯，
that come off of kind of reduced pronunciations like I'mma go, sumn.
来自像我这样的减少发音，sumn。
Um, and it seems like somehow we need something other than
嗯，好像我们需要的东西不仅仅是
canonical words if we're going to start to deal better with a lot of this text.
如果我们要开始更好地处理大量的文本，那就是规范性的话语。
Oops. Okay. So that suggests we sort of want to start doing that with our models.
哎呀。好的。所以这表明我们想要开始使用我们的模型。
And so, that's led to a lot of interest in using character level models.
因此，这引起了人们对使用角色等级模型的极大兴趣。
Um, and I mean there are sort of two extents to which you can do this,
嗯，我的意思是有两种范围可以做到这一点，
and we'll look at them both a bit.
我们会稍微看一下它们。
Um, one level is to say,
嗯，一个级别就是说，
look we're still gonna have words in our system.
看，我们的系统中仍然会有文字。
Basically, we're going to build a system that works over words,
基本上，我们将构建一个对单词有效的系统，
but we want to be able to create
但我们希望能够创造
word representations for any character sequence and we'd like to
我们想要的任何字符序列的单词表示
do it in a way that takes advantage of being able to
以一种利用能力的方式做到这一点
recognize parts of the character sequence that look familiar,
识别看起来熟悉的字符序列部分，
so that we can probably guess what vibes means.
这样我们就可以猜出什么是共鸣。
Um, and so that sort of then solves the problems
嗯，然后那样解决问题
with unknown words and we get similar words,
用不明的单词，我们得到相似的单词，
similar embeddings for words with similar terms, spellings, et cetera.
类似术语，拼写等等的类似嵌入。
But the other alternative is to say,
但另一种选择是说，
oh no, just forget about these words altogether, who needs- um,
哦不，只要完全忘记这些话，谁需要，
why don't we just do all of our language processing on sequence of characters,
为什么我们不只是对字符序列进行所有语言处理，
it'll work out fine.
它会很好的。
Um, both of these methods have been proven to work very successfully.
嗯，这两种方法都被证明非常成功。
Um, and I just wanted to dwell on that for one moment,
嗯，我只是想纠缠一下，
and that sort of goes back to my,
那种可以追溯到我的，
um, morphology slide here.
嗯，形态滑落在这里。
When people first started proposing that they are going
当人们第一次提出他们要去的时候
to build deep learning models over characters.
在角色上建立深度学习模型。
I mean, my first feeling was oh, that is never going to
我的意思是，我的第一感觉是哦，那是永远不会的
work because it sort of seemed like,
工作，因为它有点像，
okay, words have a meaning it makes sense,
好吧，单词有意义有意义，
um, that you can do something like build
嗯，你可以做类似构建的事情
a word2vec model and that's going to really be able to
一个word2vec模型，这真的能够
sort of see words and their distribution and learn
有点看单词及其分布和学习
the meanings of the words because words have a meaning.
词语的意义，因为词语有意义。
The idea that you're going to be able to say, well,
你能够说，好吧，
I'm going to come up with a vector representation of h,
我想出一个h的向量表示，
and a different vector representation of a,
和一个不同的矢量表示，
and a different vec- vector representation of t,
和t的不同vec-向量表示，
and somehow that'll be useful for representing what a hat
并且不知何故，这对于表示帽子有用
means once I put it through enough neural network layers,
意味着一旦我通过足够的神经网络层，
um, frankly it sounded pretty unconvincing to me.
嗯，坦白说这对我来说听起来很难说。
Um, but, um, I guess, you know-
嗯，但是，嗯，我猜，你知道 -
But it, it, totally works so I'm convinced now, empirical proof.
但它，它完全有效，所以我现在确信，经验证明。
And I think what we so essentially need to realize,
而且我认为我们基本上需要认识到的是，
is that with going- that yes,
就是这样 - 是的，
at some level we just have these characters that don't mean much.
在某种程度上，我们只是拥有这些并不重要的字符。
But we then have these very powerful combinatory models with a lot of parameters in them,
但是我们有这些非常强大的组合模型，其中包含很多参数，
things like recurrent neural networks and
像递归神经网络和
convolutional neural networks and that they are respectively able to, sort of, build,
卷积神经网络，它们分别能够构建，构建，
store and build representations of meaning from multi-letter groups,
存储和构建来自多个字母组的含义表示，
in such a way that they can model the meanings of
以这样的方式，他们可以模拟的意义
morphemes and larger units and therefore put together word meanings.
语素和更大的单位，因此汇总了词义。
Um, yeah. So, um,
嗯，是的那么，嗯，
one more detail on using characters,
关于使用字符的更多细节，
um, from writing systems.
嗯，来自写作系统。
So if you're a linguist you tend to think of sounds as primary.
所以，如果你是语言学家，你往往认为声音是主要的。
Those were the phonemes that we- I mentioned beforehand.
那些是我们事先提到过的音素。
You know, um, essentially,
你知道，嗯，基本上，
um, deep learning hasn't tried to use phonemes at all.
嗯，深度学习根本没有试过使用音素。
Traditional speech recognizers often did use phonemes,
传统的语音识别器经常使用音素，
but in the deep learning land,
但在深度学习的土地上，
you want to have a lot of data and the way you get a lot of data is you just use, um,
你想要拥有大量数据，以及你获得大量数据的方式，你只需要使用，嗯，
written stuff because, you know,
写的东西，因为，你知道，
it's the easily found data where you can get millions and billions of words of stuff.
这是容易找到的数据，你可以获得数百万和数十亿字的东西。
Um, so that sort of makes sense from a data point of view.
嗯，从数据的角度来看，这是有道理的。
But the thing that ends up as a little weird about that,
但最终有点奇怪的是，
is that when you're then building a character level model,
当你正在建立一个角色等级模型时，
what your character level model is,
你的角色等级模型是什么，
actually varies depending on the writing system of the language.
实际上取决于语言的书写系统。
And so you, kind of,
所以，你，有点，
have these quite different writing systems.
有这些完全不同的书写系统。
So you have some writing systems which are just completely phonemic,
所以你有一些完全音素化的书写系统，
that there are letters that have a particular sound and you say that sound.
有些字母有特定的声音，你说的是声音。
Something like Spanish is pretty much phonemic.
像西班牙语这样的东西几乎是音素。
Sometimes it's a teeny bit complicated.
有时它有点复杂。
So you might have a digraph.
所以你可能有一个有向图。
So this digraph, ngabulu, is, kind of, like,
所以这个有向图，ngabulu，有点像，
the N-G of English that is used for "ng" sound like at the end of seeing,
用于“听”声的英语NG，就像在看到结束时一样，
but, you know, basically this is just 'jiyawu',
但是，你知道，基本上这只是'jiyawu'，
each letter is a sound,
每个字母都是一个声音，
you can read it, um,
你可以读它，嗯，
and it's just, um, phonemic.
这只是，嗯，音素。
Um, that then contrasts from something like English where
嗯，然后与英语在哪里形成鲜明对比
all the non-native speakers know the spelling is terrible.
所有非母语人士都知道拼写很糟糕。
It's got this, sort of, highly fossilized,
它有这种，高度僵化，
once upon a time,
很久以前，
phonemic system in the tenth century or something.
十世纪的音素系统还是什么的。
Um, but now we have this system that words have
嗯，但现在我们有了这个系统的话
fairly arbitrary spelling that doesn't actually represent the sounds, um, very clearly.
相当随意的拼写，实际上并不代表声音，嗯，非常清楚。
But it's sort of a phonemic system.
但它是一种音素系统。
But then there are languages that use larger units.
但是，有些语言使用更大的单位。
Um, this is, um,
嗯，这是，嗯，
Canadian and Inuktitut which I just put in there because it's such a pretty writing system.
加拿大和Inuktitut，我刚刚放在那里，因为它是一个非常漂亮的书写系统。
Um, but there are a lot of languages that represent syllables by their characters.
嗯，但是有很多语言代表他们角色的音节。
Um, so you'd have something like this in Korean for example,
嗯，所以你在韩国有这样的东西，例如，
with Korean Hangul, that each, um,
与韩国韩语，每个，嗯，
letter is then being a syllable of a sort of consonant vowel combination like bar.
那么字母就是像条形一样的辅音元音组合的音节。
Um, if you can then go up a level from that and if we get back to Chinese again,
嗯，如果你可以从那里升级，如果我们再次回到中国，
well, um, this is sort of also a syllabic system, you could say.
嗯，嗯，这也是一个音节系统，你可以说。
But really, the Chinese characters are much more than just the sound.
但实际上，汉字不仅仅是声音。
They also have a meaning.
它们也有意义。
That this is really then an ideographic system
这真的是一个表意系统
where there are characters with particular meanings attached to them.
哪里有附有特殊含义的字符。
So they're, sort of, uh,
所以他们是，有点，呃，
whole morphemes in- written as one letter.
整个语素写成一个字母。
And, you know, another example of such language,
而且，你知道，这种语言的另一个例子，
um, was Egyptian hieroglyphs, if you've seen those.
嗯，是埃及的象形文字，如果你看过那些。
That they're, sort of, ideographic systems where you have letters with meanings.
他们是一种表意系统，你有字母意义。
Um, and then you have language systems that sort of mix several of those.
嗯，然后你有语言系统混合其中几个。
So Japanese is sort of a mixture of partly moraic,
所以日语有点是复杂的，
partly ideographic systems mixed together.
部分表意系统混合在一起。
So if you just,
所以，如果你只是，
sort of, start off and say,
一点，开始说，
"Okay, I'm gonna build a character-based system." That's fine.
“好的，我要建立一个基于角色的系统。”没关系。
But effectively, your character units like
但实际上，你的角色单位喜欢
letter trigrams are just very different in a language like Chinese,
字母三卦与中文这样的语言差异很大，
where commonly a letter trigram will be, sort of,
通常一个字母trigram将是，有点，
a word and a half,
一个半字，
three morphemes with meaning.
三个有意义的语素。
Whereas if you're in something like English,
如果你喜欢英语，
your character trigram will be something like T-H-O
你的角色三元组会像THO一样
which is still sort of much too small a unit to have any meaning.
这仍然是一个太小的单位，没有任何意义。
So moving right ahead.
所以前进吧。
So these two kind of approaches, um,
所以这两种方法，嗯，
one was just do a completely character level model and then the other one was,
一个只是做一个完全字符级别的模型然后另一个是，
sort of, you make use of characters
有点，你利用人物
to build bigger things that you're then gonna put something,
建造更大的东西，然后你要放东西，
like, into a more word level model.
喜欢，进入更多的单词级别模型。
So I'll do this one first and the other one.
所以我先做一个，另一个做。
So for purely character level models,
所以对于纯粹的角色级别模型，
I actually showed an example of that last time. Do you remember?
我实际上展示了上一次的例子。你还记得吗？
So there was that very deep convolutional network from
所以有一个非常深刻的卷积网络
the Conneau et-al word for text classification at the end, um,
最后，Conneau等人的文字分类，嗯，
and that just started with a big line of
而这只是从一大堆开始
characters and built these convolutional layers on top of that,
字符并在其上构建这些卷积层，
in the vision like network and classified the documents.
在视觉上像网络和分类文件。
Um, so that was, sort of, a completely character-level model.
嗯，所以那是一种完全属性级别的模型。
Um, but here's a bit more work on this.
嗯，但是这里有更多的工作。
So people for machine translation have built, um,
因此机器翻译的人已经建成，嗯，
machine translation systems that just read characters and write characters.
只读字符和写字符的机器翻译系统。
And when people first tried to do that,
当人们第一次尝试这样做时，
um, it, sort of, didn't work, right?
嗯，它，有点，不起作用，对吧？
The people thought it might help to build
人们认为这可能有助于建设
character-level models especially for languages like Chinese.
字符级模型，尤其适用于中文等语言。
But people just weren't able to build models that worked as
但人们只是无法构建有效的模型
well as word-based models and either the pre-neural,
以及基于单词的模型和前神经，
the non-neural or the neural world.
非神经或神经世界。
But gradually that started to change.
但逐渐开始改变。
So people started to have successful character-level decoders and then,
所以人们开始拥有成功的字符级解码器，然后，
sort of, around 2015 and '16,
在2015年和2016年左右，
um, people started to show,
嗯，人们开始表现出来，
look you could- can actually do machine translation very
看起来你可以 - 实际上可以做机器翻译
well at just a character level with a few asterisks.
只有一个带有几个星号的字符级别。
And so, um, here's a bit of work, um, that we did.
所以，嗯，这是一些工作，嗯，我们做了。
Um, the Luong and Manning one, from, um,
嗯，Luong和Manning一个，来自，嗯，
2015 on the last slide.
2015年的最后一张幻灯片。
So this is looking at English to Czech translation and Czech's
所以这是关注英语到捷克语和捷克语
a good language to use if you want to motivate doing things at the character level,
如果你想激励在角色层面做事，那么这是一种很好的语言，
because it had those big horrible words with lots of
因为它有很多可怕的话
morphology like the example I showed you before and I'll show you some more later.
形态像我之前向你展示的例子，我稍后会告诉你更多。
So people had built word-level models for Czech.
所以人们为捷克人建立了单词级模型。
Um, and, you know, they didn't work great,
嗯，你知道，他们工作不好，
partly because of some of these vocab problems.
部分是因为这些词汇问题。
So, um, the, sort of,
所以，嗯，那种，
word-level state of the art was at this time was 15,7 BLEU,
现阶段的单词级别是15,7 BLEU，
which as you know is much less than we will accept for full grades in your homework.
如你所知，这比我们在你的家庭作业中接受全部成绩要少得多。
[LAUGHTER] Um, but, you know,
[笑声]嗯，但是，你知道，
what counts as a good BLEU score depends on how difficult the language pair is.
什么算是一个好的BLEU分数取决于语言对的难度。
Uh, um, and so you're not doing Czech.
呃，嗯，所以你不是在做捷克语。
Um, but, um, so this was, sort of, the,
嗯，但是，嗯，所以这就是，有点，
kind of, neural MT model that we've talked about.
我们谈过的那种神经MT模型。
So it was a Seq2Seq model,
所以这是一个Seq2Seq模型，
with attention and then it had extra stuff for substituting UNKs with either,
注意然后它有额外的东西代替UNKs，
uh, single word translation or by copying stuff from the source.
呃，单字翻译或从源头复制东西。
So it was, sort of, basically,
所以它基本上是，
state of the art neural MT of 2015, got 15,7 BLEU.
2015年最先进的神经MT，获得了15,7 BLEU。
And the difference isn't big,
差别不大，
um, but we were able to show,
嗯，但我们能够表明，
look we can build this completely, um,
看，我们可以完全建立这个，嗯，
character-level model and then actually, it did fractionally better.
字符级模型，然后实际上，它做得更好。
Um, so this, sort of,
嗯，所以这个，有点像，
showed that in terms of translation quality, um,
表明在翻译质量方面，嗯，
character, purely character-based models were completely viable at
角色，纯粹基于角色的模型完全可行
capturing the meaning of text as well as word-based models.
捕获文本的含义以及基于单词的模型。
Um, was this a great result?
嗯，这是一个很棒的结果吗？
Um, in many, in some ways,
嗯，在很多方面，在某些方面，
yes, in another way, no.
是的，换句话说，没有。
I mean, this model was truly terrible to train, right?
我的意思是，这种模式训练真的很糟糕，对吧？
So it took about three weeks for us to train this model and at run-time,
所以我们花了大约三个星期的时间训练这个模型并在运行时，
it also worked very slowly.
它的工作也很慢。
And so the problem with character-level models,
所以字符级模型的问题，
if you're putting them into something like an LSTM,
如果你把它们放进像LSTM这样的东西，
is your sequences get way longer, right.
是你的序列变得更长，对吧。
So you've got about seven times as long sequences as you used to have.
所以你的序列大约是你以前的七倍。
And since there's not much information, the characters,
因为没有太多的信息，人物，
you have to do back propagation through time much further back.
你必须在更远的时候做回传播。
And so we were running back propagation through time for
所以我们在时间上跑回来传播
600 steps before we were trun- truncating it.
在我们将它截断之前的600个步骤。
And so this, sort of, made,
所以，有点，做，
maybe that was excessive,
也许这太过分了，
but it made the models, um, very slow.
但它使模型，嗯，非常慢。
But we were able to show that it was able to get some of these good effects, right.
但我们能够证明它能够获得一些好的效果，对吧。
So here's a Czech,
所以这里是捷克人，
um, translating to Czech,
嗯，翻译成捷克语，
her 11 year-old daughter,
她11岁的女儿，
Shani Bart, said it felt a little bit weird.
Shani Bart说，感觉有点奇怪。
And, um, I don't know, probably.
而且，嗯，我可能不知道。
Does anyone speak Czech, any Czech speakers?
有人说捷克语，捷克语吗？
Um, no Czech speakers?
嗯，没有捷克语人士？
Okay, um, I don't speak Czech either, um,
好吧，嗯，我也不会说捷克语，嗯，
but we can see that the [LAUGHTER] we can see that this does interesting things, right.
但我们可以看到[笑声]我们可以看到这确实很有趣，对吧。
So the second line is the human translation
所以第二行是人类翻译
into Czech which we can use for some guidance.
我们可以用捷克语来获得一些指导。
And so in particular, um,
尤其如此，嗯，
in Czech there's a word for 11 years old,
在捷克，有一个11岁的词，
um, which you can see is that blue word on the second line.
嗯，你可以看到第二行是蓝字。
And you can see that despite 11-year-old was, um,
你可以看到，尽管11岁，嗯，
that for 11-year-old it's just able to perfectly, um,
对于11岁的孩子来说，它能够完美，嗯，
produce letter by letter, um,
一个字母地生产，嗯，
the Czech word for 11 years old and that works beautifully.
11岁的捷克语，效果很好。
In contrast, for the word-level model, um,
相比之下，对于词级模型，嗯，
11 year-old was an unknown word because that wasn't in the vocabulary.
11岁是一个不为人知的词，因为这不在词汇中。
And so then it had two mechanisms to try and deal with, um, unknown words.
所以它有两个机制来尝试和处理，嗯，未知的单词。
It could either do, uh,
它可以做，呃，
unigram translation of them or it could just copy them.
unigram翻译它们或者只是复制它们。
And for whatever reason, it decided here that the best strategy
无论出于何种原因，它在这里决定了最好的策略
was to copy and so that was a complete fail.
是复制，所以这是一个彻底的失败。
Um, and if we go along for the character-level model,
嗯，如果我们继续使用角色级模型，
another thing that it gets right that's really cool,
另一件事，它是正确的，真的很酷，
um, is the name Shani Bart.
嗯，是Shani Bart的名字。
It's able to do this transliteration tasks that I mentioned just perfectly.
它能够做到我完全提到的音译任务。
And it turns that to Shani Bartova
它转向Shani Bartova
which is exactly what the human translator did as well.
这正是人类翻译所做的。
And so, you know, it's actually doing some really kind of nice, um,
所以，你知道，它实际上做了一些非常好的，嗯，
human translator, um, like things.
人类翻译，嗯，喜欢的东西。
I mean, in fact,
事实上，我的意思是，
as best I can tell from spending a bit of time on Google Translate,
我在谷歌翻译上花了一些时间，我可以说是最好的，
it actually does a pretty good job in this sentence, period.
在这句话中，它确实做得很好。
All right, this part here starts to be different,
好吧，这部分开始有所不同，
um, from the human translator.
嗯，来自人工翻译。
But it's not actually bad.
但它实际上并不坏。
It's sort of a more literal translation.
这是一种更直接的翻译。
So this citi um,
所以这个城市，
actually translates feel like in the English texts.
实际翻译感觉就像在英文文本中。
Whereas the human, sort of,
而人类，有点像，
didn't actually use the word feel in the Czech version that they just went,
实际上并没有使用他们刚刚去过的捷克语中的“感觉”这个词，
um, was a little bit,
嗯，有点儿，
um, weird or strange. So that's cool.
嗯，奇怪或奇怪。这太酷了。
Okay. So here are a couple more results from this.
好的。所以这里有更多的结果。
So here's another system that was built the next year.
所以这是另一个在明年建成的系统。
By these people Jason Lee,
这些人杰森李，
Kyunghyun Cho and Thomas Hoffman.
Kyunghyun Cho和Thomas Hoffman。
So they wanted to do something that was, I don't know,
所以他们想做一些我不知道的事情，
much more complex and neural and
更加复杂，神经质和
understanding the meaning of the text on the source side.
了解源端文本的含义。
And so they were more using the kind of technologies we saw last time.
因此他们更多地使用我们上次看到的那种技术。
So on the encoder side you started off with a letter sequence of character embeddings.
所以在编码器方面，你开始使用字母嵌入字母序列。
And then you're sort of using convolutions of four,
然后你有点使用四个卷积，
three and five of characters to get representations up here.
三个和五个字符在这里得到表示。
You're then doing a max pooling with a stride of five.
然后你以5的步幅进行最大池化。
So you're getting a max pooled representation of pieces of the text for each of the three,
因此，您将获得三个中每个文本的最大池化表示，
four and five convolutions.
四个和五个卷积。
You're then feeding that through multiple layers of
然后，你通过多层进食
highway network and feeding that through
公路网和喂养通过
a bidirectional gated recurrent unit and that's giving you your source representation.
一个双向门控循环单元，它将为您提供源代码。
On the decoder side,
在解码器方面，
it was sort of the same as our decoder,
它和我们的解码器有点相似，
it was just running a character level sequence model.
它只是运行一个字符级序列模型。
So overall, so they were doing the opposite task.
总的来说，他们正在做相反的任务。
This is Czech to English.
这是捷克语到英语。
But, so they are starting to get better scores.
但是，他们开始获得更好的分数。
But I mean actually if you're sort of looking at these different numbers,
但我的意思是，如果你有点看这些不同的数字，
where I'll explain this system more in a minute,
我会在一分钟内解释这个系统，
I mean it sort of seems like the place where they get a lot of value is that using
我的意思是它看起来像是一个有很多价值的地方就是使用它
the character level decoder gives them a lot of value by
字符级解码器为它们提供了很多价值
this very complex model on the source side is giving them almost no value at all.
源端的这个非常复杂的模型几乎没有任何价值。
One even more recent paper,
最近的一篇论文，
so this is Colin Cherry and fellow researchers at Google.
所以这是Colin Cherry和Google的研究人员。
So they last year did one more exploration of
所以他们去年又做了一次探索
doing LSTM sequence to sequence
做LSTM序列来排序
style models of comparing word and character-based models.
比较单词和基于字符的模型的样式模型。
And this is English to French and this
这是英语到法语和这个
is um, Czech to English which is just what we were doing.
是嗯，捷克语到英语，这正是我们正在做的事情。
And so in both cases when you have a big model,
在这两种情况下，如果你有一个大型模型，
the character model wins for them.
角色模型为他们赢了。
The blue model comes out on top but the sort of interesting thing as you
蓝色模型出现在顶部，但有点像你一样有趣
sort of see these different effects depending on
有点看到这些不同的效果取决于
the morphological complexity of the language.
语言的形态复杂性。
So for a language like Czech,
所以对于像捷克这样的语言，
it's a really good idea,
这是一个非常好的主意，
if you want to build a good model,
如果你想建立一个好的模型，
to use character level that they're getting about a BLEU point of difference there,
使用他们所获得的关于BLEU差异点的角色等级，
whereas for a model without putting French or English there's
而对于没有放法语或英语的模型
actually a tiny but very little gain from using a character level model.
使用角色等级模型实际上是一个微小但很少的收获。
Okay so let me just explain these models,
好的，让我来解释这些模型，
so these models are models of different sizes.
所以这些型号是不同尺寸的型号。
So these models are using bidirectional LSTM encoders and one-directional LSTM decoders.
因此，这些模型使用双向LSTM编码器和单向LSTM解码器。
So the simplest model just has
所以最简单的模型就是这样
a shallow bidirectional LSTM encoder and a two layer LSTM decoder.
浅双向LSTM编码器和双层LSTM解码器。
The middle model has a three deep stack of
中间模型有三个深层堆栈
bidirectional LSTM encoders and a four deep stack of LSTM decoders.
双向LSTM编码器和四层深度LSTM解码器。
And the most complex model has a six deep stack of
而最复杂的模型有六个深层堆栈
bidirectional LSTM encoders and an eight deep stack of LSTM decoders.
双向LSTM编码器和8个深度LSTM解码器堆栈。
This is where it helps to work at Google.
这是它有助于在Google工作的地方。
Probably for your projects,
可能对你的项目来说，
you don't want to go beyond three or four. Stay over here.
你不想超越三四个。留在这里。
Okay yeah so, so these are the results.
好的，是的，所以这些都是结果。
So basically what you're finding is if you're making
所以基本上你发现的是你正在制作的
sort of smaller models you're better off with words,
一些较小的模特，你最好用文字，
but as you go to big models especially if you're in a morphologically rich language,
但是当你去大模特时，特别是如果你是一个形态丰富的语言，
you clearly start to win from the characters.
你明显开始从角色中获胜。
But there is still a loss which is essentially
但基本上仍然存在损失
exactly the same loss that we were suffering from in 2015, right?
和我们在2015年遭受的损失完全相同，对吧？
This is the time graph and so these are the same three models as over here,
这是时间图，因此这些是与此处相同的三个模型，
it's just the axis is changed to sort of sum the total number of LSTM layers.
它只是将轴更改为LSTM层总数的总和。
And so essentially, if you're at the word level,
基本上，如果你在单词级别，
you can run any of these three models and they are fast that you can be translating in
你可以运行这三种模型中的任何一种，它们很快你可以翻译
sort of not much time but for the character level models your slope is much higher.
有点时间，但对于角色等级模型，你的坡度要高得多。
So it starts to get quite expensive to run the deep character level models.
因此，运行深度字符级模型开始变得非常昂贵。
Okay, so that's that section.
好的，那就是那个部分。
So then chugging along.
所以然后继续。
I then wanted to look at other ways of doing things.
然后我想看看其他做事方式。
And so these are models that in some sense still do have words but where
所以这些模型在某种意义上仍然有文字，但在哪里
we're going to want to sort of build word representations out of pieces.
我们想要构建单独的单词表示。
And there are essentially two families of ways that people have explored doing this.
基本上有两种方式可供人们探索这样做。
One way of doing it is to say look we just want to use
一种方法是说我们只想使用它
exactly the same architecture as we use for a word model
与我们用于单词模型的结构完全相同
except our words aren't really going to
除了我们的话并非如此
be words at least sometimes they're going to be pieces of words.
至少有时它们会成为一些单词。
And so those are often called word piece models.
因此，这些通常被称为单词模型。
And in particular, there's one commonest way of doing it.
特别是，有一种最常用的方法。
It's called BPE, which I'll go through in some detail.
它被称为BPE，我将详细介绍它。
The other alternative is to say,
另一种选择是说，
well, we're gonna kind of make a mixture or a hybrid.
好吧，我们要做一个混合物或混合物。
So our main model is going to work in terms of words but we're
因此，我们的主要模型将在单词方面起作用，但我们是
going to have some kind of facility where we can construct a representation,
会有一些我们可以建造代表的设施，
for otherwise unknown words,
对于其他未知的单词，
by doing things that at a character or a lower level.
通过做一个角色或更低层次的事情。
And I'll show you a bit of that as well.
而且我也会告诉你一点。
Okay, so this is BPE.
好的，这就是BPE。
BPE is actually a pretty simple idea which has nothing to
BPE实际上是一个非常简单的想法，它什么都没有
do with deep learning but the use of BPE has sort of become
深入学习，但BPE的使用已经成为现实
pretty standard and successful for representing pieces of words to allow you to
相当标准，并成功表示允许你的单词
have an infinite vocabulary
有一个无限的词汇
while an infinite effective vocabulary while actually working with a finite vocabulary.
而实际上使用有限的词汇表时，无限有效的词汇量。
So the origins of Byte Pair Encoding and
所以字节对编码的起源和
the name byte pair has nothing to do with natural language processing or neural nets,
名称字节对与自然语言处理或神经网络无关，
we're just writing a compression algorithm.
我们只是在写一个压缩算法。
So this is something like compressing your documents with gzip.
所以这就像使用gzip压缩文档一样。
So what basic Byte Pair Encoding is,
那么基本的字节对编码是什么，
that you've got a collection of stuff with bytes and you are
你有一些字节的东西，你是
looking for the most frequent sequence of two bytes and you say,
寻找最常见的两个字节序列，你说，
okay, I'm going to add that sequence of two bytes as
好吧，我要将两个字节的序列添加为
a new element to my dictionary of possible values.
我的可能值字典的新元素。
And that means I can have 257 different values for bytes so to
这意味着我可以有257个不同的字节值
speak that I can shrink the length of
说我可以缩短长度
my sequence and I can repeat over and do that again.
我的序列和我可以重复并再次这样做。
And so essentially, this work suggested,
基本上，这项工作建议，
well we can apply this kind of compression algorithm and use it as
我们可以应用这种压缩算法并将其用作
a way of coming up with pieces of words that were
提出一些单词的方法
useful, doing it not strictly with bytes despite
虽然有用，但不严格按字节操作
the name but instead with characters and character n-grams.
名称，但改为字符和字符n-gram。
And so the most common way to do this with
所以最常见的方法就是这样做
characters and character n-grams and if you're up with modern times,
字符和字符n-gram如果你现代的话，
you know that means there's unicode and you can represent
你知道这意味着有unicode，你可以代表
all of these lovely letters like Canadian Inuktitut's
所有这些可爱的信件，如加拿大Inuktitut的
syllabics and stuff like that.
音节和类似的东西。
But there's actually a problem with Unicode,
但实际上Unicode存在问题，
which is there actually a lot of Unicode characters.
实际上有很多Unicode字符。
I forget the number theoretically.
我理论上忘了这个数字。
I think there's about 200,000 possible Unicode characters.
我认为大约有200,000个可能的Unicode字符。
But at any rate, if you want to handle a bunch of languages which include East Asian languages,
但无论如何，如果你想处理一堆包含东亚语言的语言，
maybe you need something like 20,000 characters and that's sort of a lot.
也许你需要20,000个字符，这有点像。
So there are actually some people who've literally gone back to bytes and said,
所以实际上有些人真的回到了字节并说，
"You know 200,000, that's a really big vocabulary.
“你知道20万，这是一个非常大的词汇。
I don't want to deal with anything."
我不想处理任何事情。“
Sorry, 200,000 is a really big vocabulary.
对不起，200,000是一个非常大的词汇。
I don't even want to deal with anything that large.
我甚至不想处理那么大的事情。
So why don't I actually just do these kind of algorithms over bytes?
那么为什么我实际上不只是在字节上做这些算法呢？
And so that means that in UTF-8 encoding,
这意味着在UTF-8编码中，
Chinese characters take three bytes each.
汉字各占三个字节。
And so you're actually have to- you only get whole characters if you
所以你真的必须 - 如果你，你只能获得整个角色
actually merge together several bytes that are common sequencers.
实际上将几个字节合并为常见的序列发生器。
Okay. So more concretely,
好的。更具体地说，
um, how does this work?
嗯，这是怎么回事？
So we're sort of doing this bottom-up clustering of short sequences.
所以我们有点做这种自下而上的短序列聚类。
So we start with a unigram vocabulary,
所以我们从unigram词汇开始，
which is all of the Unicode characters and some data.
这是所有的Unicode字符和一些数据。
We then sort of ask, what's the most frequent ngram here?
然后我们问一下，这里最常见的ngram是什么？
Um, initially it will be a bigram pair and we add that to our vocabulary.
嗯，最初它将是一对二元组，我们将它添加到我们的词汇表中。
So if we start off, you know,
所以，如果我们开始，你知道，
we can take our text that's- um,
我们可以把我们的文字拿来，
I'll come back to this in a minute.
我马上回过头来看看。
Let's assume we have a text that has been divided into words so we do have word tokens.
假设我们有一个文本被分成单词，所以我们有单词标记。
And so we can represent as a dictionary and say here are some words with their frequency.
因此我们可以将其表示为字典，并在这里说出一些带有频率的单词。
Um, and so now we look for a common letter sequence and we say, "Oh, es."
嗯，所以现在我们寻找一个共同的字母序列，我们说，“哦，es。”
That occurs nine times, um,
这发生了九次，嗯，
in this data because we have the counts for the words on the left side.
在这个数据中，因为我们对左侧的单词有计数。
So, um, we start with our vocabulary being all the individual letters.
所以，嗯，我们的词汇是所有单个字母。
We find a commonest letter sequence like es,
我们找到一个最常见的字母序列，如es，
and so we say, "Let's clump that together and make that a new thing in our vocabulary."
所以我们说，“让我们一起团结起来，把它作为我们词汇中的新东西。”
So now we've got an extra thing in our vocabulary.
所以现在我们的词汇量还有额外的东西。
And now what's the commonest ngram sequence that clumped something?
现在什么是最常见的ngram序列聚集了什么？
Well, actually all of these es's are followed by t,
嗯，实际上所有这些es都跟着t，
so we also have es,
所以我们也有es，
t with frequency nine,
t频率为9，
and so we can add that to our vocabulary.
所以我们可以将它添加到我们的词汇表中。
And then we ask again, well,
然后我们再问一遍，好吧，
what's another common letter sequence?
什么是另一个常见的字母序列？
Let's see, there are seven cases of o double- well,
让我们看看，有七个双井的情况，
I guess there are seven cases of either l o or o w,
我猜有七个案例都是lo或ow，
so we can lump those and then we can lump
所以我们可以把它们混为一谈然后我们可以把它们混为一谈
again and make an lo w. So if we sort of run this,
再次做出一个低谷。所以，如果我们运行这个，
we start to build these clumps of common letter sequences,
我们开始构建这些共同字母序列的团块，
and so common bits like est,
像est这样常见的比特，
but also just common words,
但也只是常用词，
something like that in English will very quickly be
像英语这样的东西很快就会出现
clumped together and be a unit of our vocabulary.
聚集在一起，成为我们词汇的一个单元。
Um, and so we do that for a while.
嗯，所以我们这样做了一段时间。
So normally what we do is we decide
通常我们所做的就是决定
a vocabulary size that we want to work with. We say, "Okay.
我们想要使用的词汇量。我们说，“好的。
I want to work with a vocabulary size of 8,000 words."
我想使用8,000字的词汇量。“
That'll mean my model will be fast,
这意味着我的模型会很快，
and we just sort of keep doing this until we have 8,000 things in our vocabulary.
我们只是继续这样做，直到我们的词汇量中有8000个东西。
And that means that our vocabulary will have in it
这意味着我们的词汇将包含在其中
all single letters because we started with them and it'll
所有单个字母，因为我们从它们开始，它会
have common subsequences of words like the es and the est that are now in our vocabulary,
有像我们词汇中现在的es和est这样的单词的共同子序列，
but also have whole words whenever there're common words, like, you know,
每当有常见的词语时，也会有完整的词汇，比如，你知道，
the, and too, and with,
这个，也是，和，
and so on, will become parts of our vocabulary.
等等，将成为我们词汇的一部分。
Um, and so then when we have a piece of text we can do
嗯，等等，当我们有一段文字时，我们可以做
a deterministic longest piece segmentation of words,
单词的确定性最长片段，
and we will say that is our eeset of word pieces.
我们会说这是我们的文字片段。
And so for an input piece of text,
对于输入的文本，
we turn into word pieces,
我们变成了单词，
and then we just run it through our MT system as if we were using words,
然后我们只是通过我们的MT系统运行它，好像我们正在使用单词，
but really it's pieces of words,
但实际上它是一些单词，
and then on the output side,
然后在输出端，
we just concatenate them back together as needed.
我们只是根据需要将它们连接在一起。
Okay. So we get this sort of automatic word-based system.
好的。所以我们得到了这种基于单词的自动系统。
And that's proved to be a very successful system.
事实证明这是一个非常成功的系统。
So this idea of using byte pair encoding sort of really
所以这种使用字节对编码的想法真的很好
emerged in 2015 and then in 2016, uh,
出现在2015年，然后在2016年，呃，
workshop on machine translation which has been the main sort of annual competition for
机器翻译研讨会一直是年度竞争的主要方式
MT systems that the several top systems were built using byte pair encoding.
几个顶级系统使用字节对编码构建的MT系统。
If you look at last year's competition,
如果看一下去年的比赛，
there's a bit more variety,
有更多的变化，
but really a number of the top systems are still using byte pair encoding,
但实际上许多顶级系统仍在使用字节对编码，
that's just been a good way to do things.
这只是做事的好方法。
So for Google's Neural Machine Translation,
那么对于谷歌的神经机器翻译，
they effectively use of- a variant of byte pair encoding.
它们有效地使用了字节对编码的变体。
So they don't use exactly the same algorithm, um,
所以他们不使用完全相同的算法，嗯，
they use a slightly different algorithm where they're
他们使用的算法略有不同
using a language model and they're saying,
使用语言模型，他们说，
what- what- rather than just using pure counts,
什么 - 而不仅仅是使用纯粹的计数，
they're saying, "What clumping together would maximally reduce
他们说，“聚集在一起会最大限度地减少
the perplexity of my language model and clump those things and repeat over?"
我的语言模型的困惑，并把这些东西弄成团块并重复过来？“
And so they did- they've done two versions of this model.
所以他们做了 - 他们已经完成了这个模型的两个版本。
So the first version, the wordpiece model kind of like, um,
所以第一个版本，wordpiece模型有点像，嗯，
byte pair encoding assumed that you have an initial tokenization
字节对编码假定您有一个初始标记化
to words and then you're just sort of having pieces of words,
单词，然后你只是有一些单词，
um, using this algorithm.
嗯，使用这个算法。
And then they did a second version, um,
然后他们做了第二个版本，嗯，
the sentencepiece model which you can find at this GitHub site which said, "Well,
你可以在这个GitHub网站找到的句子模型说：“嗯，
it's problematic if we need to tokenize into words first
如果我们需要首先将其标记为单词，这是有问题的
because then we need to have a tokenizer for
因为那时我们需要有一个tokenizer
every language and that's a lot of work."
每种语言，这都是很多工作。“
Um, so maybe instead of that,
嗯，也许不是那样，
we could just sort of treat,
我们可以只是对待，
go from a character sequence,
从一个字符序列，
retain whitespaces and regard that as something that's part of the clumping process,
保留空格并将其视为集合过程中的一部分，
and so that, um,
所以，嗯，
you just build your word pieces which
你只需要建立自己的文字片段
commonly will have spaces on one side or the other of them, um,
通常会在一侧或另一侧有空间，嗯，
because often things inside a word are the
因为一句话里面的东西经常是
commoner- more common clumps and you build those up,
布衣 - 更常见的团块，你建立起来，
and that's proven to be quite successful.
这被证明是非常成功的。
Um, in particular, one place where some of you might see this,
嗯，特别是，有些人可能会看到这个，
um, is, um, we've yet to get to describing it in the class really,
嗯，是，嗯，我们还没有真正在课堂上描述它，
but there's been this recent work which we actually talk about next week in class, are
但是最近我们在课堂上实际谈到的这项工作是
building these transformer models, in particular,
建造这些变压器模型，特别是
Google has released this BERT model which gives you
谷歌发布了这款BERT模型
very good, um, word representations.
非常好，嗯，字表示。
And if you download BERT and try and use it,
如果您下载BERT并尝试使用它，
what you will find out is it doesn't operate over words,
你会发现它不会在文字上运作，
it operates over word pieces.
它运行在文字片段上。
Um, and so it has a large vocabulary.
嗯，所以它有很大的词汇量。
It's not a vocabulary of like 8,000 words.
这不是像8000字的词汇。
I forget the number,
我忘记了号码，
but the models have a large vocabulary,
但模型的词汇量很大，
but they're still not a huge vocabulary and it's using word pieces.
但它们仍然不是一个庞大的词汇，它使用的是文字。
So lots of words are in the vocabulary.
所以词汇量中有很多单词。
So if you look at the English model,
所以如果你看看英文模特，
it not only has words like f in it,
它不仅有像f这样的词，
but it even has words like Fairfax and 1910s,
但它甚至有像费尔法克斯和1910年代这样的词，
which aren't that common.
这并不常见。
Um, but it's nevertheless to cover all words,
嗯，但它仍然涵盖所有的话，
it's again using this wordpiece idea.
它再次使用这个词组的想法。
So if I want a representation for the word hypatia, um,
所以如果我想要一个hypatia这个词的表示，嗯，
that's not in the vocabulary,
这不在词汇表中，
and so I'm making it up of pieces.
所以我正在制作碎片。
There's an h representation,
有一个代表，
and then in the BERT version,
然后在BERT版本中，
which is different to the Google NMT version,
这与Google NMT版本不同，
the non- the non-initial word pieces are represented with two hashes at the start,
非初始单词片段在开头用两个哈希表示，
so I can put that together with h##yp etc.,
所以我可以把它与h ## yp等放在一起，
and this would be my representation of hypatia.
这将是我对hypatia的代表。
So effectively, I have word vectors, um,
如此有效，我有单词向量，嗯，
for four word pieces,
四个字，
and then I have to work out what to do with them.
然后我必须弄清楚如何处理它们。
The simplest and quite common way is I just average the four of them.
最简单和最常见的方式是我只平均其中的四个。
And there are obviously other things you could do.
显然，你可以做其他事情。
You could ConvNet and maxpool or you could run
您可以使用ConvNet和maxpool，也可以运行
a little LSTM or something to put together a representation.
一点点LSTM或什么东西来组合一个表示。
Okay. Yeah. So- so those were the models that, um,
好的。是啊。所以那些模型，嗯，
sort of, worked with pieces of words to give you
有点像，用词语来给你
infinite vocabulary and ran them through a normal system.
无限的词汇，并通过正常的系统运行它们。
The other possibility is to say, "Well,
另一种可能性就是说，“好吧，
we wanna work with characters so we can deal with an infinite vocabulary,
我们想与角色合作，这样我们就可以处理无限的词汇，
but we're gonna sort of incorporate those into a bigger system."
但我们会把它们整合到一个更大的系统中。“
And a whole bunch of work has done this
而且一大堆工作已经完成了
and in some sense it's a fairly obvious thing to do.
从某种意义上讲，这是一个相当明显的事情。
Um, so this work in 2014 was one of the early ones.
嗯，所以2014年的这项工作是早期的工作之一。
So they said, "Well,
所以他们说，“好吧，
we could start with characters.
我们可以从角色开始。
We can do a convolution over the characters to generate word embeddings,
我们可以对字符进行卷积以生成单词嵌入，
and then we can use those word embeddings for something in a higher level model."
然后我们可以在更高级别的模型中使用这些嵌入词。“
Um, this was actually sort of a fixed window model for doing part of speech tagging.
嗯，这实际上是用于进行部分语音标记的固定窗口模型。
Um, that makes sense.
嗯，这很有道理。
Instead of a convolution,
而不是卷积，
you could use LSTM.
你可以使用LSTM。
So this was work from a year later,
所以这是一年后的工作，
and they said, "Well,
他们说：“好吧，
we're also gonna build up, um,
我们也要积累起来，嗯，
word representations from characters.
字符的单词表示。
And the way we're gonna do it is we're gonna run character level Bi-LSTMs,
而我们要做的就是运行角色级Bi-LSTMs，
concatenate the two final states,
连接两个最终状态，
and we're gonna call that outward representation,
我们要称之为外向代表，
and then we're gonna put that word representation into a
然后我们将把这个单词表示放入一个
language model which is then a higher level LSTM that works along a sequence of words."
语言模型，然后是一个更高级别的LSTM，沿着一系列单词工作。“
And I thought I'd just- Oh, yeah.
我以为我只是 - 哦，是的。
Words, are they training uh, like character-
话说，他们是训练呃，喜欢性格 -
Yeah. Oh yeah, that's very important to realize.
是啊。哦，是的，这一点非常重要。
Yes so yeah so if you're learning- you'll learn- I mean this is the hidden layer.
是的所以是的，如果你正在学习 - 你将学习 - 我的意思是这是隐藏层。
I guess I'm not actually showing the input layer but for the input layer
我想我实际上并没有显示输入层，而是显示输入层
you're learning a vector for each character.
你正在为每个角色学习一个向量。
So effectively you're doing the same kind of thing we saw
所以你有效地做了我们所看到的同样的事情
before that you're starting with random representations for each character.
在此之前，您将从每个角色的随机表示开始。
You've got this embedded inside a word sequence LSTM,
你已将它嵌入到单词序列LSTM中，
your goal is to minimize the perplexity of the higher level LSTM as,
你的目标是最大限度地减少高级LSTM的困惑，因为，
um, as a language model and so it filters back its gradients.
嗯，作为一种语言模型，所以它过滤掉它的渐变。
So it's wanting to come up with character vectors such that if it
所以它想要提出角色向量，如果它
produces good word vectors which produces low, um, perplexities.
产生良好的单词向量，产生低，嗯，困惑。
Good question. Um, so here's, um,
好问题。嗯，所以这里，嗯，
a slightly more complex version of trying to
尝试稍微复杂一点的版本
do this that's a bit more recent where again the idea is can we build
做到这一点，这是一个更近期，我们可以建立的想法
a good language model by starting out from characters
一个好的语言模型，从字符开始
and wanting to exploit sort of related sub words and rare words.
并希望利用一些相关的子词和罕见的词。
And so they built sort of this kind of
所以他们建造了这种类型
this more stacked complex model that we'll go through the stages of wherefore
这个更加堆叠的复杂模型，我们将经历其中的各个阶段
we start with a word represented as characters.
我们从一个表示为字符的单词开始。
We have character embeddings which we build
我们有自己构建的字符嵌入
into a convolutional network and then we head upwards.
进入卷积网络，然后我们向上。
So if we take that one piece at a time,
所以，如果我们一次拿一件，
um, so you have a character embedding for each character.
嗯，所以你有一个角色嵌入每个角色。
Um, you'll then have a convolutional layer which
嗯，你会有一个卷积层
then sort of rep, has various filters that work over those,
然后排序代表，有各种过滤器，这些过滤器，
um, character sequence of two, three and four grams of characters.
嗯，两个，三个和四个字符的字符序列。
So you're getting representations of parts of words.
所以你得到了部分单词的表示。
Um, then from those convolutional networks you're then doing max pooling over time which
嗯，然后从那些卷积网络，你随后随着时间的推移做最大的汇集
is effectively sort of like choosing which of
实际上有点像选择哪一个
these n-grams best represents the meaning of a word.
这些n-gram最能代表一个词的含义。
Um, then what they do after that is so at that point
嗯，那之后他们做的就是那个时候
they've got an output representation for character n-grams,
他们有一个字符n-gram的输出表示，
and so then they feed that into a highway network like we talked about a bit last time.
然后他们把它送进高速公路网，就像我们上次谈到的那样。
And then the output of that then at the word level,
然后在单词级别的输出，
um, goes into an LSTM network,
嗯，进入LSTM网络，
and this LSTM network is now word-level LSTM network,
而这个LSTM网络现在是字级LSTM网络，
and you're trying to sort of maxim- minimize
而你正试图将最大化最小化
perplexity like for the neural language models we saw earlier.
像我们之前看到的神经语言模型一样令人困惑。
Um, so what could they show with this?
嗯，那么他们能用什么表现呢？
Well, the first thing they could show with it is that it
嗯，他们可以用它来展示的第一件事就是它
actually again just works well as a language model despite that skepticism
尽管存在怀疑态度，但实际上它再次作为一种语言模型很有效
that I hadn't told you of about the fact of
我没有告诉过你关于这个事实的事实
the matter is you could build these kind of character level models and
问题是你可以建立这种角色级别的模型和
train them and they work to a first approximation as well as word-level language models.
训练他们，他们工作的第一个近似以及词级语言模型。
But one of the observations that they make is that you can be
但他们所做的一个观察是你可以
getting as good results but with much smaller models.
获得良好的结果，但模型更小。
So up at the top here are
所以在这里是顶部
the character level LSTM models and word ones that the models they built.
字符级LSTM模型和他们建立的模型的单词。
And here are a whole bunch of models over this data-set.
这里有一大堆关于这个数据集的模型。
Um, and so as time went by perplexities have been going down,
嗯，随着时间的推移，困惑一直在减少，
gone to 78,4 and their point was well we can
去了78,4他们的意思很好
build pretty much as good a character model with 78,9 perplexity but
以78,9的困惑构建非常好的角色模型但是
our model is actually much smaller, this model here has
我们的模型实际上要小得多，这个模型在这里有
52 million parameters whereas our model that
5200万参数，而我们的模型
works on a character level has only 19 million parameters.
在角色级别上工作只有1900万个参数。
So it's about 40% of the size.
所以它的大小约为40％。
And that seems,um, kind of interesting.
这似乎，嗯，有点有趣。
But perhaps what's more interesting is to sort of peek inside it and see what
但也许更有趣的是窥视它并看看它是什么
happens with the representation of words when
发生在单词的表示时
built out of characters and this part is sort of actually a bit cool.
用字符构建而且这部分实际上有点酷。
Um, so what this is showing is for words that are up to the top while,
嗯，所以这显示的是那些高达顶部的单词，
his, you, Richard, trading.
他，你，理查德，交易。
It's asking what other words are most
它在问其他单词最多
similar to it according to the word representations that's computed.
与根据计算的单词表示类似。
And the top part is the output of a word level LSTM model and that's sort of okay.
顶部是单词级LSTM模型的输出，这有点好。
Richard comes out as similar to Jonathan,
理查德出来与乔纳森相似，
Robert, Neil and Nancy et cetera.
罗伯特，尼尔和南希等。
While although letting though minute mainly okay.
虽然虽然让分钟主要还好。
But it's sort of interesting what happens with their character level models,um,
但是他们的角色等级模型会发生什么有趣的事，嗯，
and so in particular, um,
特别是，嗯，
what's kind of interesting is like first of all you remember they sort of had
有趣的是，首先你记得他们曾经有过
the character embeddings that went through the convolutional layer and the max pooling.
经过卷积层和最大池的字符嵌入。
And if at that point you ask what things are most
如果在那时你问什么是最重要的事情
similar that basically it's still remembering things about characters.
类似的，基本上它仍然记得有关人物的事情。
So the most similar words to while,
那么最相似的话，
chile, whole, meanwhile and white.
智利，整体，同时和白色。
So at least for the sort of first ones they all end in LE.
所以至少对于那些他们都以LE结尾的那些。
And you see that pattern elsewhere right close to Richard,
你在其他地方看到理查德那样的模式，
hard, rich, richer, richter that hard ends in ARD, rich.
坚强，富裕，富裕，富有，在ARD中坚硬，富有。
So you're just sort of getting this character sequence similarity,
所以你只是得到这个字符序列的相似性，
it's not really doing meaning at all.
它根本就没有意义。
But interestingly when they're then putting it through the highway layers,
但有趣的是，当他们将它穿过高速公路层时，
that the highway layers are suc- successfully learning how to
高速公路层成功学习如何
transform those character sequence representations
转换那些字符序列表示
into something that does capture meaning.
进入能够捕捉意义的东西。
So if you then say at the output of
所以，如果你然后在输出中说
the highway layers what words are most similar then it seems to be working pretty well,
高速公路层层覆盖哪些词最相似然后它似乎工作得很好，
While was similar to meanwhile, Richard is similar to Edward, Gerard, Edward with Carl.
与此同时，理查德与爱德华，杰拉德，爱德华和卡尔相似。
They're sort of now working much more like
他们现在的工作方式更像
a word level model in capturing semantic similarity.
捕获语义相似度的词级模型。
So that seems kind of cool.
所以这看起来很酷。
Um, so then they say well what about if we ask about
嗯，那么如果我们问的话，他们会说得好
words that aren't in the vocabulary of the model.
不属于模型词汇的单词。
Well, if they're not in the vocabulary of the model,
好吧，如果他们不在模型的词汇中，
the word level model can't do anything and so that's why you get those dashes there.
单词级别模型不能做任何事情，所以这就是你在那里获得那些破折号的原因。
And what they're wanting to show is that
而他们想要表现的是
the character level model still works pretty well.
角色等级模型仍然很好用。
So if you give it look with seven O's in the middle of
所以如果你看看中间有七个O.
it that it's correctly deciding that look,
这是正确决定外观，
look, look, looking are actually
看，看，实际上是
the most similar words to that which is actually working very nicely.
最相似的单词，实际上工作得非常好。
And some of the other examples are similar, computer-aided,
其他一些例子类似，计算机辅助，
is seen as most similar to computer-guided,
被视为与计算机指导最相似，
computer-driven, computerized, computer, you're getting pretty similar sensible results.
计算机驱动，计算机化，计算机，你得到了非常相似的明智结果。
And then the little picture on the,
然后是小图片，
um, right is sort of, um,
嗯，对，有点像，嗯，
showing, um, one of these 2D visualizations of the units that have been learned.
显示，嗯，已经学习的单元的2D可视化之一。
And so the red,
所以红色，
the red things are word character prefixes,
红色的东西是单词字符前缀，
the blue things are character suffixes,
蓝色的东西是字符后缀，
the orange things are hyphenated things
橙色的东西是连字符的东西
like in the middle of computer-guided and gray is everything else.
就像在计算机引导的中间，灰色就是其他一切。
And so there's some sort of sense,
所以有某种意义，
with which it's picking out different important parts of words.
它正在挑选出不同的重要部分。
Okay. Um, and that's why also I guess just another good example of how you can sort of
好的。嗯，这就是为什么我想也是另一个很好的例子，你可以如何排序
compose together different kinds of building blocks to
把不同种类的积木组合在一起
make more powerful models that you might
制作更强大的模型
also want to think about for your final projects.
也想考虑你的最终项目。
Okay.
好的。
Um, so here's
嗯，所以这里
back to one other example from a neural machine translation system
回到神经机器翻译系统的另一个例子
of doing this hybrid architecture that has word-level and character level.
这种具有词级和字符级别的混合架构。
I showed you earlier a purely character level model.
我之前向您展示了一个纯粹的角色等级模型。
I mean we built that out of interest to see
我的意思是我们出于兴趣而建立起来
how well it did but we were sort of really wanting to build
它有多好，但我们真的很想建立
a hybrid model because that seemed like it would be much more practical
混合模型，因为它似乎更实用
to build something that translated relatively quickly and well.
建立一个相对快速和良好翻译的东西。
Um, so the idea was we'd mainly build
嗯，所以我们的想法主要是建造
a word-level neural machine translation system but we'd
我们是一个单词级神经机器翻译系统
be able to work with character level stuff when we had rare or unseen words.
当我们有罕见或看不见的单词时，能够使用字符级别的东西。
Um, and that turned out to work pretty,
嗯，结果很漂亮，
um, successfully at improving performance.
嗯，成功地提高了性能。
So the idea of that model is this.
所以这个模型的想法是这样的。
Um, that we're going to run a pretty standard, um,
嗯，我们打算运行一个非常标准的，嗯，
sequence to sequence with attention LSTM neural machine translation system.
序列序列与注意LSTM神经机器翻译系统。
In my pic- I mean, it's actually a four-level deep system but in my picture I
在我的照片中 - 我的意思是，它实际上是一个四级深度系统，但在我的照片中我
showed less than four levels stacked to make it easier to see things.
显示不到四个级别堆叠，以便更容易看到事物。
And we're going to run this with a reasonable vocabulary of 16,000 words.
我们将以16,000字的合理词汇来运行它。
So for common words we just have word representations that we're feeding into
因此，对于常见的词语，我们只是有词表示，我们正在加入
our neural machine translation model but for words that aren't in the vocabulary we're
我们的神经机器翻译模型，但对于我们不在词汇表中的单词
going to work out a word representation for them by using a character level LSTM,
通过使用字符级LSTM来计算出他们的单词表示，
and conversely, when we start to generate words on
相反，当我们开始生成单词时
the other side we have a soft max with a vocabulary of 16,000.
另一方面，我们有一个软的最大值，词汇量为16,000。
It could just generate words like [NOISE] but one of those words is the UNK symbol.
它可以生成像[NOISE]这样的单词，但其中一个单词是UNK符号。
And if it generates the UNK symbol we then run a- we take
如果它产生了UNK符号，那么我们就运行一个 - 我们采取
this hidden representation and feed it in as
这个隐藏的表示形式并将其作为
the initial input into a character level LSTM and then we have the character level
初始输入到字符级别LSTM然后我们有字符级别
LSTM generate a character sequence until it generates
LSTM生成一个字符序列，直到它生成
a stop symbol and we use that to generate words. Um-
一个停止符号，我们用它来生成单词。 UM-
Okay. So we end up sort of with this sort of
好的。所以我们最终会遇到这种情况
hybrid composed stack of eight LSTM layers. Uh, yeah.
由8个LSTM层组成的混合组合。呃，是的
[inaudible] and you always get some probability for the UNK symbol.
[听不清]你总是得到UNK符号的概率。
So if you wanted to get the- the proper gradient,
所以，如果你想获得适当的梯度，
you- you'll always have to run it for every word but what- what do you-?
你 - 你总是要为每个单词运行它，但是你做什么 - ？
I would often say, you only run during training,
我经常说，你只在训练期间跑，
you only run the character level LSTM when the UNK symbol receives the highest likelihood.
只有在UNK符号获得最高可能性时才运行字符级别LSTM。
So we-
所以我们 -
What is that?
那是什么？
So at training, at training time,
所以在培训时，在培训时间，
there's a determinant piece of tech, right?
有一个决定性的技术，对吧？
You know the source and you know the target,
你知道来源，你知道目标，
and so we're, and at training time,
所以我们是，在训练时，
we've already decided our vocabulary, right?
我们已经决定了我们的词汇，对吗？
That we've just decided what are the 15,999 most common words,
我们刚刚确定了最常见的15,999个单词，
those and UNK are our vocabulary.
那些和UNK是我们的词汇。
So for both the input and the output side,
所以对于输入和输出端，
we know which words aren't in our vocabulary.
我们知道哪些词不在我们的词汇中。
And so if it's not in our vocabulary,
所以，如果它不在我们的词汇中，
we're running this one.
我们正在运行这个。
If if what was the output is not in our vocabulary,
如果输出的内容不在我们的词汇表中，
we're running that one, and otherwise we're just not running it at all, yeah.
我们正在运行那个，否则我们根本就没有运行它，是的。
So and and the bit that I didn't explain but is actually important perhaps
所以，而且我没有解释但实际上也许很重要
related like when we're calculating a loss that we can back
相关的，就像我们计算一个我们可以支持的损失
propagate, that sort of up here,
传播，在这里，
there are sort of two losses.
有两种损失。
There's a loss at the word level that you know you'd like to in this position,
在这个位置，你知道你想要的单词级别有一个损失，
give probability 1 to generating UNK but really,
给出概率1来生成UNK，但实际上，
this model we'll softmax, we'll say UNK is you know probability 0,2 or whatever.
这个模型我们将softmax，我们会说UNK你知道概率0,2或其他什么。
So there's a loss there and then secondarily,
所以那里有一个损失，其次是，
there's a particular sequence of characters you wanna generate and you've also got
你想要产生一个特定的角色序列，你也得到了
a loss because you've met the probabilities you put over the characters.
失败是因为你已经遇到了你对角色的概率。
Um, So then, um,
嗯，那么，嗯，
I think we- I think Abby sort of briefly mentioned this.
我想我们 - 我认为艾比有点简单地提到了这一点。
Commonly, the decoders do some kind of
通常，解码器会做某种事情
beam search to consider different possibilities before deciding,
光束搜索在决定之前考虑不同的可能性，
um, the highest probability one over a sequence of words.
嗯，一个词序列的概率最高。
And so this was doing a slightly more complex version of that.
所以这是一个稍微复杂一点的版本。
So there's a word-level beam search when running it and then
因此，在运行它时会有一个字级光束搜索
also doing a character level beam search to consider different possibilities.
还进行字符级光束搜索以考虑不同的可能性。
And so if you wanna integrate the the two of those together.
所以，如果你想将这两者结合在一起。
Um, but essentially, um,
嗯，但基本上，嗯，
this worked pretty well.
这非常有效。
Um, so, um, this was the winning system at WMT 2015 which
嗯，所以，嗯，这是WMT 2015的获奖系统
used 30 times as much data and ensembled together
使用了30倍的数据并整合在一起
three other systems compared to the data that was provided for the task.
与为该任务提供的数据相比，其他三个系统。
This was the system I showed before, they got 18,3.
这是我之前展示的系统，他们得到了18,3。
Um, and if you remember our character,
嗯，如果你还记得我们的角色，
purely character level system got 18,5.
纯粹的角色级别系统得到18,5。
Um, then by building this hybrid system,
嗯，然后建立这个混合系统，
that we were able to build a much better system that was about 2,5 BLEU points better,
我们能够建立一个更好的系统，大约2,5 BLEU点更好，
um, than after- than either this word level or the character level system.
嗯，比之后 - 比这个单词级别或字符级别系统。
So that was kind of nice, um,
所以这很好，嗯，
and in particular that was the state of the art at the time.
特别是当时的艺术水平。
Now of course, if you were paying very close attention,
当然，如果你非常关注，
that's now nowhere near the state of the art.
现在已经远远不是最先进的了。
Because when I showed you that slide way earlier of the Google system,
因为当我向您展示Google系统之前的那种幻灯片时，
you will have noticed that they have
你会注意到他们有
much higher numbers in the 20s, but that's what happens as the years go by.
20年代的数字要高得多，但这就是随着岁月的流逝而发生的事情。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
But here's an example that shows
但这是一个显示的例子
these different systems working and some of the mistakes they make.
这些不同的系统工作和他们犯的一些错误。
Um, here's a cherry picked example, um,
嗯，这是一个樱桃挑选的例子，嗯，
where our system, the hybrid system,
我们的系统，混合动力系统，
works perfectly because what- that's what you expect to see.
是完美的，因为那是你期望看到的。
Um, and so, you know,
嗯，你知道，
you can see some of the defects of things that can go wrong.
你可以看到一些可能出错的东西的缺陷。
Um, so in this case,
嗯，所以在这种情况下，
you know the character level system didn't work here because it just sort
你知道角色级系统在这里不起作用，因为它只是排序
of starting with the Steph, it sort of seemed to free associate,
从斯蒂芬开始，它似乎是自由联想，
um, a completely made up name that doesn't really have anything to do with the source.
嗯，一个完全组成的名字，与源码没有任何关系。
So that one isn't very good.
所以一个人不是很好。
Um, the word level system went bang here,
嗯，字级系统在这里爆炸，
so you remember when it generates an UNK,
所以你记得它什么时候生成UNK，
the word level system would have when it generates, it's using attention.
单词级别系统在生成时会有，它正在使用注意力。
So when it wants to generate, um,
所以当它想生成时，嗯，
it has attention back to words and the source.
它重视文字和来源。
And when it generates UNK has two strategies.
而当它产生UNK有两个策略。
It can either do unigram translation of the word that it's maximally
它可以对单词的单词翻译进行最大化
putting attention on or it could copy the word that it's maximally putting attention on.
注意或者它可以复制它最大限度地关注的词。
Um, so in this case,
嗯，所以在这种情况下，
it chose to translate the word that it was maximally putting attention on but the word it
它选择翻译它最大限度地引起注意的那个词，而不是它
was maximally putting attention on was after rather than diagnosis.
最大限度地关注是在经过而不是诊断之后。
And so you just get this po po coming out of after,
所以你只是让这个po po出来了，
after and we've completely lost the word.
之后，我们完全失去了这个词。
Um, and in this example, in this example,
嗯，在这个例子中，在这个例子中，
how a hybrid system, um,
混合动力系统怎么样，嗯，
just ends up working beautifully and gives you exactly the right translation.
只是最终工作得很漂亮，并为您提供完全正确的翻译。
Yeah. Um, of course,
是啊。嗯，当然，
it's not always that good in the real world.
它在现实世界中并不总是那么好。
Um, so here's a different example.
嗯，所以这是一个不同的例子。
So this is the example I showed before with the 11-year-old daughter.
所以这就是我之前与11岁女儿展示的例子。
Um, and in this example,
嗯，在这个例子中，
the hybrid model has the same strength of the character model.
混合模型具有与角色模型相同的强度。
It correctly generates 11 years old at a character level in its translation,
它在翻译中正确生成了11年的字符级别，
but you know this time, for whatever reason,
但是你知道这一次，无论出于何种原因，
it's the hybrid model that goes bang in
它是混合模型
generating the names and it translates Shani Bart as Graham Bart.
生成这些名字并将Shani Bart翻译为Graham Bart。
Um, whereas the character level model gets it right.
嗯，而角色等级模型是正确的。
Um, actually, I think this is one of the weaknesses of
嗯，实际上，我认为这是其中一个缺点
this hybrid model compared to the character level model.
这种混合模型与人物等级模型相比较。
That because of the character level generator is
因为字符级生成器是
kind of this sort of second level.
有点像这种二级。
For the purely character level model,
对于纯粹的角色级别模型，
it's able to use the character sequence as conditioning context very effectively.
它能够非常有效地使用字符序列作为条件上下文。
Whereas our hybrid model,
而我们的混合模型，
although we feed the hidden representation of
虽然我们提供隐藏的表示
the word level model in as
单词级别模型
the starting hidden representation of the character level model,
字符级模型的起始隐藏表示，
it doesn't have any representation further
它没有任何进一步的表示
back than that of what's in the word level model.
比单词级别模型中的更低。
And so it tends to not always do as good a job at representing,
因此，它往往并不总能在表现方面做得很好，
of capturing the context that allows it to do translation of things like names.
捕获允许它进行名称之类的翻译的上下文。
Okay. Um, very- almost finished but there's
好的。嗯，非常接近完成但是有
just sort of one thing I wanted to mention before
只是我之前想提到的一件事
the end which is almost a practical thing.
结束这几乎是一件实事。
Um, So we started off with word embeddings,
嗯，所以我们开始使用单词嵌入，
but now we've been talking a lot of character level models.
但现在我们一直在谈论很多角色级别的模型。
So surely, just for word embedding, you should be able to do useful things with them,
当然，只是为了嵌入字，你应该能够用它们做有用的事情，
with characters or pieces of words.
用字符或单词。
And that's something that people start to play with.
这是人们开始玩的东西。
So in this Cao and Rei paper they said well
所以在这篇Cao和Rei论文中，他们说得很好
let's train a Word2vec model using exactly the same, um,
让我们使用完全相同的训练Word2vec模型，嗯，
loss as Word2vec uses but let's,
Word2vec使用但是让我们失去了
um, rather than having word representations,
嗯，而不是用词表示，
let's start with character sequences and run
让我们从字符序列开始并运行
a bidirectional LSTM to work out word representations,
双向LSTM来计算单词表示，
and we'll then sort of be effectively
然后我们就会有效
training this more complex model where we're learning
在我们学习的地方训练这个更复杂的模型
character embeddings and LSTM parameters and that will give us our word representations.
字符嵌入和LSTM参数，这将为我们提供单词表示。
And that's an idea that people have continued to play with,
这是人们继续玩的想法，
and so in particular I just wanted to mention these FastText embeddings.
所以我特别想提到这些FastText嵌入。
Um, so a couple of years ago,
嗯，几年前，
um, people now at Facebook,
嗯，现在Facebook的人，
the same Tomas Mikolov who did the original Word2vec,
做原始Word2vec的Tomas Mikolov一样，
brought out a new set of embeddings,
推出了一套新的嵌入，
the FastText embeddings and their goal was to sort of
FastText嵌入和他们的目标是排序
have a next-generation Word2vec, um,
有下一代Word2vec，嗯，
which is sort of an efficient fast, um,
这是一种有效的快速，嗯，
word vector learning library, um,
单词矢量学习图书馆，嗯，
but it was better for rare words and languages with lots of morphology.
但对于具有大量形态学的罕见词汇和语言来说，它会更好。
And the way they did it was that they sort of essentially took the Word2vec skip
他们这样做的方式是他们基本上采用了Word2vec跳过
gram model but they augmented it to put in character n-grams.
克模型，但他们增加它以加入字符n-gram。
So more precisely, this is what they did.
更确切地说，这就是他们所做的。
So, um, when you had a word,
所以，嗯，当你说了一句话，
my example word is where,
我的例子是在哪里，
for some n-gram size you represent it as a set of n-gram.
对于某些n-gram大小，您将其表示为一组n-gram。
So this is kind of just about like those, we called phonemes I mentioned
所以这就像那些，我们称之为音素
right at the beginning where you have a kind of a boundary symbol,
在一开始你有一种边界符号，
so you know the beginning of the word.
所以你知道这个词的开头。
So if the length is three you have beginning of word WH, WHE, HER,
所以如果长度为3，你就有WH，WHE，HER这个词的开头
ERE, RE end of word,
ERE，RE结尾，
as pieces of representation.
作为代表作品。
And then you have an additional one for just the whole word.
然后你还有一个额外的单词。
So you do still have whole word representations in this model.
所以你在这个模型中仍然有完整的单词表示。
So where is represented by six things and so
那么六件事代表哪里呢？
then you're going to use all six of those things in your computation.
那么你将在你的计算中使用所有这六个东西。
Um, so if you sort of remember the guts of
嗯，所以如果你有点记得那些胆量
Word2vec that what you were doing was you were doing
Word2vec，你正在做的是你在做什么
these vector dot products between your context representation
这些矢量点产品介于您的上下文表示之间
and your center word representation.
和你的中心单词表示。
So they're going to do exactly the same thing but for
所以他们会做同样的事情，但是
the center word they're gonna use all six of these vectors.
他们将使用所有这六个向量的中心词。
All the vectors corresponding to all six of
所有向量对应于所有六个
these representations and they're going to sum them.
这些陈述，他们将总结他们。
And so you're just doing a simple summing operation,
所以你只是做一个简单的求和操作，
and that's sort of then giving you your representation of similarity.
然后那就是给你相似的表示。
Um, very precisely, they don't quite do that
嗯，非常确切地说，他们并不那么做
because there's a hashing trick but I'll leave that out.
因为有一个哈希技巧，但我会把它留下来。
But what they're able to show is that that model actually works pretty successfully.
但他们能够展示的是，该模型实际上非常成功。
So these are words similarity scores,
所以这些是单词相似度得分，
skip gram, they're all CBOW,
跳过克，他们都是CBOW，
and then this is the sort of new model,
然后这就是那种新型号，
um, that, um, uses these kind of n-grams.
嗯，那个，嗯，使用这种n-gram。
And in this, um,
在这，嗯，
you know at least for one of the English data sets,
你知道至少有一个英文数据集，
it doesn't get any better.
它没有变得更好。
Um, but what they especially notice this is for languages that have more,
嗯，但他们特别注意到这是有更多的语言，
morp- more morphology that you're sort of getting some fairly clear gains.
更多的形态，你可以获得一些相当明显的收益。
70, 69 onto 75,
70,69到75，
59, 60 on to 66 in the right column,
59,66到右栏66，
so then these wordpiece models do give them a better model of
所以这些文字模型确实给了他们一个更好的模型
words and just practically FastText, um,
单词，只是几乎FastText，嗯，
library now has sort of word embeddings for about 60 or 70 different languages,
库现在有大约60种或70种不同语言的单词嵌入，
so it's sort of a good source of word embeddings for multilingual applications.
所以它是多语言应用程序的一个很好的字嵌入源。
Okay, I think I am done.
好的，我想我已经完成了。
So thanks a lot and see you again next week.
非常感谢，下周再见。